opinioninsight.com 2016-06-20

# Kinesis Privacy Policy

This privacy policy is effective May 1, 2013. 

**Purpose and Scope**  
This policy discloses what information Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC gathers about you when you visit kinesissurvey.com. It describes how we use that information and how you can control it. It does NOT pertain to information gathered within survey instruments or by joining survey panels that may utilize our software. For information about how the data in a particular survey or panel is being used, please contact email support for that particular site/project.

**Information About What Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC Gathers and Tracks**  
Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC collects two kinds of information about users:

  1. Data that users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, entering contests, completing surveys, or buying directly from us; and
  2. Aggregated tracking data we collect when users interact with us.

**Personal Information**  
We use the personal information you provide voluntarily to send information you’ve requested. The specific use of your personal information varies, depending on how you contact us:

  * When you subscribe to Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC mailing lists to receive Kinesis news and product information, you must provide an email address. We never sell or rent the email address you provide when subscribing to our lists.
  * When you enter a contest or survey, we may ask for your name, address, and email address so we can administer the contest and notify winners.

We release personal information when we believe that release is appropriate to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC, our users, or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Aggregated tracking information**  
We analyze visitors’ use of our sites by tracking information such as pageviews, traffic flow, search terms, and click through. We use this information to improve our sites.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Cookies & Advertising**  
A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser when you visit our sites. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your computer, so that we can provide you with personalized information and features. We do not use cookies to track user traffic patterns. You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies or to block cookies. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features or functions.

**Services**  
This site contains links to other sites. Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Web Sites.

**Contests & Surveys**  
We may run contests or surveys on our site in which we ask our users for contact information (like their email address). We use the customer contact information from the entry form to send the user information about our company and its products, or to contact them when it becomes necessary (notices about updates, patches, etc.). Users may opt out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below).

**Security**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All the data regarding users, their computers’ system information and benchmark results are stored on a server. This server is located in a locked and guarded space and only authorized Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC personnel have access to the database containing given user names and passwords.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on www.kinesissurvey.com. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users via email. Users will be able to opt out of any new use of their personal information.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us and from our partners at the point where we request information about the user. This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database so that they no longer receive future communications or access to our other services:

  1. You can Contact Us, stating your request.
  2. You can reply to any unwanted communications that you receive, stating your request.

**Reviewing personal data**  
You can review and validate the information, that we have collected about you via Contact Us and request a review on your personal data.

**Use of Kinesis Software by Licensees-Protection of Data by Kinesis**  
Kinesis Survey Technologies, LLC licenses software to businesses that conduct market research on consumers and business decision makers. The Kinesis software provides the researcher with tools to program and deploy online and mobile surveys and provides the tools necessary to build, maintain, and reward panels of individual participants.

  The companies that license the Kinesis software can program and deploy online and mobile surveys and manage online panels. They invite individuals to give their opinions on a wide variety of research subjects. The invitees may come from an established research panel, a customer list, a purchased email list, banner ads, or other recruiting methods. Personal data such as name, email and physical address, age, gender, profession, income, and other demographic data are often collected in order to support research conclusions about certain subsets of survey respondents and to be able to fulfill rewards for participation that are often a part of the research process.

  The Kinesis software is most often hosted in the US at a secure data center in Austin, TX. Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC has arranged for this hosting as part of the service customers receive when licensing Kinesis software. Therefore, EU citizens that participate in research panels and surveys prepared and managed by companies that license Kinesis software may have personal data stored on servers located in the US at the Austin, TX data center.

  When licensees deploy surveys and panels we will not access or allow unauthorized access to licensee created data or provide it to any third parties unless specifically requested by the licensee or required to by law.

  Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC utilizes a PCI level 1 compliant with SAS70 type 2 certification data center and extensive hardware and managerial procedures to protect from unauthorized access, copying, manipulation, or forwarding of data stored on our servers. We require our licensees to comply with CAN-SPAM and other professional standards when using Kinesis services and software. Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC reserves the right to suspend access should it come to our attention that a licensee is violating US or other country privacy or other laws of which we are aware (such as EU safe harbor principals) in its use of Kinesis software. Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC cannot be held responsible should it not discover or become aware that its software use by a licensee may violate US or other country laws.

**US/EU Safe Harbor Adherence**

 ****

**Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC adheres to the Safe Harbor framework developed by the Department of Commerce in coordination with the European Commission**. The Safe Harbor framework promotes data security and privacy protection and includes procedures to insure that the terms and conditions are adhered to and supported by those companies who have agreed to the terms and conditions of Safe Harbor and have formally certified as such. Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC has secured the services of The Better Business Bureaus (BBB EU Safe Harbor Program) to provide an independent recourse mechanism should a complaint remain unresolved regarding Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC’s compliance with the standards set forth in the safe harbor framework.

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC via our online Contact Us form, or call +001 512 590 8300.

Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. **If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by Kinesis Survey Technologies LLC, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at[www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint.**

Kinesis Survey Technologies has certified its compliance with the Safe Harbor rules and can be found on the US Department of Commerce list of companies certifying at: [ http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/SHList.nsf/WebPages/Texas](http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/SHList.nsf/WebPages/Texas)

Kinesis Survey Technologies is also listed on the Better Business Business Bureaus EU/US Safe Harbor Participants site at [http://us.bbb.org](http://us.bbb.org/)

EU and Swiss consumers with any BBB EU Safe Harbor privacy complaints may access the complaint form here: [**www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints**](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints).

**Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web Site, you can Contact Us.
